God on Trial is a history, war, drama film directed by Andy de Emmony.
In the Jewish tradition of arguing with God, Jewish
prisoners in Auschwitz decide to put God on Trial.
Isaac, played by Josef Altin.
Ricard, played by Ashley Artus.
Moche, played by Dominic Cooper.
Blockaltester, played by Lorcan Cranitch.
Hugo, played by David de Keyser.
Schmidt, played by Stephen Dillane.
God on Trial is a 2008 British television play written by Frank
Cottrell-Boyce, starring Antony Sher, Rupert Graves and Jack Shepherd.
The play takes place in Auschwitz during World War II.
The Jewish prisoners put God on trial in absentia
for abandoning the Jewish people.
The question is whether God has broken his covenant with the Jewish
people by allowing the Germans to commit genocide on them.
It was produced and shown by the BBC on 3 September 2008.
Production was supported by PBS, which screened the play
as part of its Masterpiece anthology.
The play is based on the Elie Wiesel play The Trial of God.
Cottrell-Boyce describes this tale as "apocryphal".
Wiesel later stated that the event was true, and that he had witnessed it.
According to Cottrell-Boyce, producer Mark Redhead "had been trying to turn the story into a film
for almost 20 years by the time he called me in 2005 to write the screenplay."
The film explores themes of holocaust (shoah),
auschwitz-birkenau concentration camp, debate.
The tone is emotional.